https://zbmath.org/privacy-policy/

50
100 (default)
200
Default Display Format
MathJax (default)
LaTeX
Default Documents Sorting
Newest first (default)
At FIZ Karlsruhe – Leibniz-Institut für
Informationsinfrastruktur GmbH (hereinafter referred to as “FIZ
Karlsruhe”, “we” or “us” ) ensuring the security and protection
of your personal data is a primary concern. We would therefore
like to inform you on how, to what extent, and for which
purposes we collect, process and use your personal data.
Controller
Controller according to Art. 4 para. 7 of the General Data
Protection Regulation (GDPR) is
FIZ Karlsruhe – Leibniz-Institut für Informationsinfrastruktur GmbH
Hermann-von-Helmholtz-Platz 1
76344 Eggenstein-Leopoldshafen
You will find further information on the controller in our
Legal Notices.
What we do:
FIZ Karlsruhe offers you web pages for information purposes and
online products (hereinafter summarized as our “digital
offers”). We process personal data collected from the visitors
of our digital offers exclusively in compliance with data
protection laws. The legal basis of data protection can be
found in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the
German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz) in
its valid form and the German Telemedia Act (Telemediengesetz).
The sections below will inform you about the type and scope of
data we collect, the reasons why we collect them, and the way
in which they are used and processed. We use these data only
for the purposes we specify.
In general, you may use our web pages without providing any
additional personal information.
If you would like to use our online products, you will need a
user account (individual access) for which we will collect
personal data from you. In addition, different rules may apply
about which you will be informed separately in the respective
Terms and Conditions.
I. What do we know about your use of our digital offers?
1. Log Files
By default, our server will store the following user
information in a log file whenever our digital offers are
used:
IP addresses used
If you have logged in: your user ID and allocation to your institution (if any)
Date and time of access
Volume of data sent and received (bytes)
Address of the web page from which our page was accessed (referrer)
We use the log file data exclusively
to trace our customers’ movements through our digital
offers in case of malfunctions in order to identify the
malfunction,
for customers in accordance with the relevant laws and
based on separate terms and conditions or terms of use.
The legal basis for the usage modalities mentioned above is
Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f
GDPR.
We will not use the user data contained in the log files, in
particular the IP address, for any purposes other than those
mentioned above.
We will delete the log files and the information contained
therein after 36 months at the latest. This does not apply in
cases where there is specific indication that our digital
offers were used in an illegal manner. In this case the data
will be stored until the matter is settled.
2. Collection and analysis of user data for statistical purposes
We also use the above mentioned log files to statistically
analyze our visitors’ user behavior. From these files we
generate usage statistics for customers according to library
standards in accordance with the relevant laws and based on
separate terms and conditions or terms of use.
We do not identify the place from which you access our digital
offers (geolocalization). This does not apply in cases where
there is specific indication that our digital offers were
supposed to be used in an illegal manner.
3. Cookies
Cookies are text files that we store on your computer. They
enable us to monitor when and how you use our digital offers
over a defined period of time. We use cookies for various
purposes that are described below.
If you do not want any cookies to be stored on your computer,
you must disable this function according to the instructions
provided in your web browser. As a consequence, however, you
will no longer be able to use certain features of our website
(e.g., auto-saving of facets or language settings).
3.1 Cookies storing settings and preferences
We use cookies to store your settings, e.g., your preferred
language. We also use cookies to authenticate subscribed users.
A pop-up message within our digital offer will notify you
that we are using cookies. If you accept this, we will store
the information in question in a cookie on your computer.
Usually, the lifetime of such cookies ranges from some months
to more than one year.
3.2 Cookies required for technical reasons in order to allow for sessions
We use cookies for technical reasons to be able to
unambiguously allocate the large number of simultaneous visits
to the respective users. They enable us to create “sessions”
during which you can perform actions built upon one another.
These cookies are automatically deleted at the end of a session
(by logout or by closing the tab or the browser used to access
our digital offer).
4. Sharing content through social networks
We do not use any mechanisms that automatically transmit data
to providers of social networks when our digital offers are
visited. Some of our digital offers allow for the sharing of
pages through social networks.
To be able to share a page, you
have to activate the button of the social network by mouse
click first. Only upon your activating the button the provider
of the social network will learn that you are using our digital
offer. You have to carry out this activating process for each
individual page of our digital offer you would like to share.
II. What other personal data do we collect and how do we use them?
1. Receiving additional information
When using our website, you may also request further
information or support in using our digital offers, i.e., if
you
provide feedback online,
participate in a promotional offer or product test,
request an e-mail notification,
subscribe to a newsletter, or
subscribe to a mailing list.
In this case we will ask for the necessary personal data and a
separate declaration of consent, if required. Your consent will
then constitute the legal basis according to Art. 6, para. 1
lit. a GDPR.
Receiving information from us is not mandatory. If we have
obtained your consent, your personal data will only be used for
the purposes covered by this consent.
Revocation of consent
You have the right to revoke your consent to the use of
personal data connected with the aforementioned services at any
time. Please note that you will no longer be able to use these
services after you have revoked your consent.
2. Using FIZ Karlsruhe’s online products
In general, you will need a user account and/or a contract to
use our online products. Depending on the product, you can
either register directly online or have the account created by
our customer service.
If necessary, we will provide you with further information
relevant to the separate Terms and Conditions or Terms of Use
for our online products. The regulations contained therein and
the purposes for which we are using the personal data that are
mentioned in these Terms and Conditions or Terms of use have
the following legal basis:
If you have concluded a contract with us in order to
use our digital offers, the personal data required to
perform this contract are processed according to Art.
6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR.
Beyond performing our contractual obligations we will
process your data if this is necessary in order to
safeguard a legitimate interest of our own or of third
parties. The legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.
If we request your consent to the processing of
personal data, this consent will be the legal basis
according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.
We may be bound by law to process your personal data,
for example, to fulfil tax obligations. In this case the
data are processed according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c
GDPR.
If we have to process your data for a task that is of
public interest, the data are processed according to
Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e GDPR.
The personal data are stored for the duration of the contract
or as long as there is another legal basis for it, and for the
relevant or mandatory retention periods.
3. Personal Metadata
In some of our digital offers we are processing metadata from
scientific publications (including publications of data).
Metadata describe a publication in order to identify it and to
make it easily retrievable. These metadata also contain
personal information that was either published by the
respective persons themselves or that we have taken from
publicly available sources:
Names of the authors or the persons who generated the data
Persistent, unambiguous person identifiers (e.g., ORCID,
VIAF, GND-ID, WikiData-ID)
Information about which institution the persons belong to
Hyperlinks to authors’ academic websites
These personal metadata are usually processed together with
other, non-personal descriptive metadata (e.g., the title of
the publication, abstract, copyright holder). The purposes for
which the data are processed and published include
Supporting the scientific discourse,
Searching for and providing publications,
Acknowledging and correctly attributing scientific
achievements,
Archiving global research knowledge, and
Persistently providing the descriptive metadata as a set of
research data.
All metadata are permanently stored within the scope of
providing our services.
The legal basis for processing and publishing these data is
GDPR Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f.
The descriptive metadata are processed for research and storage
purposes and are required in order to fulfil the specific
purposes mentioned above. Therefore, the persons concerned may
only object on grounds of their particular situation and if the
interests, basic rights and fundamental freedoms of the persons
concerned prevail over the legitimate interest mentioned above.
We are always interested in correcting faulty metadata and
completing incomplete sets of metadata, if necessary.
Therefore, we are very grateful for any hint on missing data
and errors to be corrected. Just contact us at one of the
addresses listed in section V.6.
through websites, data interfaces (“API“) or as complete
download in various machine-readable data formats.
2. Personal data that were not yet published
Your personal data will not be sold or in any other way
disclosed to any third parties for marketing or other business
purposes without your consent. Please note that other websites
that can be accessed through our digital offers may request
personal data from you. This data protection policy does not
apply to any third-party sites.
Personal data will only be disclosed to public authorities if
this is required by law, in particular in order to protect the
national or public security, or for the purpose of criminal
prosecution.
FIZ Karlsruhe reserves the right to use your data to assert or
to defend legal claims.
IV. Data security
FIZ Karlsruhe’s digital offers have appropriate security
measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, and unauthorized
alteration of your personal data. These include
encryption of data transmitted between your end device and our digital offer,
protection of our computer systems by modern firewall systems,
regular security updates,
regular backups, and
login and access control.
We strive to best protect your personal data in compliance with
the relevant data protection laws. However, FIZ Karlsruhe
cannot absolutely ensure the security of the data you transmit
to us. Therefore, that transfer of data is at your own risk.
In your own interest, please be careful and responsible
whenever you are online and protect your personal information
against unauthorized third-party access.
V. Your Rights
1. Right of access by the data subject (Art. 15 GDPR)
Upon request, FIZ Karlsruhe will inform you in writing or by
e-mail if your personal data are stored with us and which forms
of your personal data are stored with us. If you find factual
inaccuracies in your personal data previously transmitted to
FIZ Karlsruhe, please contact us
by e-mail or at the
address below and indicate the required changes or corrections.
2. Right to rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
Should you detect errors in your personal data stored by us, or
if your personal data have changed, you have the right to have
these data corrected or updated.
3. Right to erasure (Art. 17 GDPR)
You have the right to have your personal data we have stored
blocked or deleted, provided that this does not conflict with
any of the reasons listed in Art. 17 para. 3 lit. a-e GDPR.
4. Right to restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)
You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal
data stored with us under the conditions outlined in Art. 18,
para. 1 GDPR.
5. Right to data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)
You also have the right to receive your personal data that you
have provided to us in a structured, common, machine-readable
format.
6. Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR)
You also have the right to object at any time to the processing
of your personal data on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or
f GDPR on grounds relating to your particular situation.
To exercise your rights please contact us informally by mail or
e-mail at one of the addresses listed below and describe your
concern as precisely as possible. If necessary, we will ask you
for further information in order to be able to examine your
request.
editor@zbmath.org
Address of our Data Security Officer:
FIZ Karlsruhe – Leibniz-Institut für Informationsinfrastruktur GmbH
datenschutzbeauftragter@fiz-karlsruhe.de
You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent
supervisory authority.
VI. Questions
If you have any further questions relating to our data
protection policy, to our digital offers or to the relevant
modalities of their access and use, please send an e-mail to
our customer service department:
editor@zbmath.org.
×
This website uses cookies for the purposes of authentication and preference information. By continuing to use the website, you agree to this. If you would like to learn more about cookies, please click on the Privacy Policy.
